We have seen that deck allows the insertion and deletion on both sides there, here and there front.
So for that, we have two types of insertion.
The insertion at the front and the insertion at the rear.
So this operation adds that element at the front.
Let's check the position of the front at the first step.
So this is that cue this is that the cue that we are going to allow the insertion into it at the front.
So consider this DAG.
We have seven three one at position zero one two, respectively, and we have created the front at the
zero position zero and rear at position two because we have added the elements.
So there will be moving into position.
No index number two.
The second step, if the front less than one, then reinsure lies the front equal to end minus one,
the last index.
So we have the front, we move it back less than one than it initialized the front end, minus one to
be at their last index, pointing to the left index and keep that here at the beginning.
Don't worry, we are going to implement these all of these codes and the deck implementation in C,
and we are going to solve the exercise in Java.
So we are going to implement the deck in C and Java as we have implemented all of the previous data
structures.
OK.
The last thing we need to do is decrease front by one and add the new key five into the array of front.
You see guys that if we are going to insert that data at the front of the deck, we need to move the
front to the left index and then we insert the key that we are going to implement and add it to that
deck at the front.
OK.
Add the position array having thrown out.
OK, this is the trick behind adding and removing.
We will see the removing also and the deck insertion like in the front and rear.
We use that array at index front or array at index pretty.
OK.
This is the method that we are going to to see in the next videos, but this is for the deck insertion
at the front.
This is implemented in C and we are going to implement it in Java later on would check this that this
the this method took into bear ray.
Point there, the item, the front and the rear as arguments and we initialize AKC, then we start making
that condition, check if the deck is full, that we have seen it in previous videos and we start.
If it is at the front equal one minus one, then put the front equal to the item.
This is the insertion and the third case.
If the rear does not equal to max minus one, then we start by making assigning C and assigning K and
looping through this array in order to insert it correctly at the specific position.
This is the deck insertion at the front.
Let's see.
Deck insertion at the end.
Already, this operation element to the area, consider the first step, check if the area is full,
it is not full.
So we will continue the second step if the deck is full Re Shirley's rear equal to zero and else increase
rear by one.
We increase here because we are inserting that at the end.
We start by using the rear, so we add a rear by one, increase rear by one and adds and you key five
into the array at index rear.
OK.
You see, guys, this is the best practice of deck insertion every year.
So we have two pointers the front and the rear, and we are working on them.
So we have moved that here in the next button, increase it by one.
And if it is empty, then we are going to insert the array that the new number into the array at index
rear.
And this is the deck insertion at the rear.
Method the the perimeter that they want their item for front and rear.
And we start checking if the deck is full, then don't make anything if the front equal equal minus
one.
Then add it to that added directly array at index three.
And if they're equal maximum minus one, then make a start by making K equal to front minus one and
add it to that empty position.
Using that, this cone, I want from you to write them down and memorize them, because that may be
maybe a ask.
Maybe it will be ask it in the interviews and in the exams.
OK, so we will see the deck implementation, complete deck implementation in C and.